SECURITY ENGINEER

Professional Summary

I'm an experienced professional eager to grow in the fields of Cloud Computing, Network Security, software and business. 10+ years' experience Bachelor's equivalent in Computer Science with honors majoring in Network Security and Web Programing and Development, I continue to learn and contribute as much as I can in the field. I also continue to strive to grow and earn skills that helps contribute to business growth. I have Windowsdiverse experience in multiple areas which proves to be valuable in overcoming many professional challenges. I have extensive experience in business management roles ranging from employees, consulting to engineering. In each role, I've streamlined inefficient processes and/or provided stakeholders with recommendations for improvement. With prior government, business, and management experience as well as extensive academia in various fields and specialties, I continue to strive for personal and professional growth. TECHNICAL SKILLS Result- Oriented, Talented Multi- tasker Multi-Site operations expert with a full understanding of network configurations and Windows operating systems. Troubleshoot applications and system errors. And the ability to follow the NIST compliance model for securing networks. VPN installing and configuring tunnels for connecting to internal network for sit users. Installing Security Patches. Worked with Remedy and Service Now ticketing systems for documentation of user and system issues as well as special projects. Computer and Technical Support- assisting users or working unsupervised to resolve Network, System or Software issues. Installation and Setup- Upgrading, Repairs, Troubleshooting, Maintenance of desktops, laptops, printers, and Thin clients also all other peripherals including but not limited to Signature devices, scanners and other medical equipment. Microsoft Team Systems Installation of software packages, upgrade and update software. Writing Network Policies and Procedures. user manuals, documentation of Support issues. High Profile Presentations Trouble shooting and support of smart phone. Network mobile access for company smart phones, Cisco Smart Devices and thin clients. Troubleshoot applications and system errors. And the ability to follow the NIST compliance model for securing networks.

Skills

- Ability to install, configure and administer Network Directory services.
- Knowledge of security for network hardware, software, and data including physical security and backup procedures; relevant tools; encryption and protection from viruses
- Computer forensic tools
- Risk Assessments, Continuity of Operation Plans, System Security Plans, and Security Test and Evaluation Procedures
- Incase software for retrieving deleted and lost Data C++, HTML/HTML5, CSS3, FLASH CS5-6 and Animate CC (Action Script), ColdFusion, PHP, JavaScript, J query, Flex Builder, Flex 4, ASP.Net, Visual Studio, Mobil Apps,
- Tools used for editing: Dream Weaver, Note Pad, Note Pad +++, WordPress
- DATABASE'S AND QUERY'S
- My SQL, SQL DB and Query Language,
- Cold Fusion DB and Query Language
- PROGRAMING ABILITIES FOR NETWORK ADMINISTRATION
- PowerShell Scripting, Batch files
- Solar Winds, Wireshark, PS Tools, SNMP, WMI and WSUS, SCCM
- SOFTWARE/PROTOCOLS
- MS Office97-360, XP/Outlook, Word, Excel, Access, Power Point, Visio, MS Project, Cisco call manager, Helpdesk software, Abram Accounting Software and Payroll software, R&R Report Writer,
- Acrylic Wi-Fi, TCP/IP
- REMOTE DESKTOP APPLICATIONS
- Team Viewer, VNC, PC Anywhere, Dame Ware, Carbon Copy, Ghost, Backup Exec, McAfee ASAP, McAfee Enterprise, Norton Enterprise, Telnet, FTP, HTML, Dream Weaver, Front Page 2000, TCP/IP, IPX/SPX (installed and configured for Windows 95, 98, XP, ME NT4.0, Win Server 2000, Server 2008, Server 2012 Novell 5.0, Unix2.6, and Linux 6.1), Unix Vision, HIPAA compliant Medical Field software. PS Tools for administrative work
- SYSTEM HARDWARE MAINTENANCE
- Computer Laptop, Desktop (Client and Server), Mobile Devices, Tablets, Security Camera's, Surveillance equipment, Game Systems

Work History

January 2015 - January 2017 SECURITY ENGINEER | Motion Recruitment | Upland, CA

- Digital forensics software to retrieve files that are deleted or for imaging of hard disks for court proceeding.
- Software that is used by the FBI for gathering evidence at the scene of a crime.
- Trained in the ability to fix network attacks by malware and spyware and manipulate the windows registry to fix root kit attacks.
- Ethernet concepts, media, and Operations.
- INSTALLATION CONFIGURED SUPPORTED Linux Red Hat 7 Linux Ubuntu, Kali Linux, and the various White Hat techniques.
- Use for penetration of network to find vulnerabilities or security flaws.
- UTM Dell SonicWall T300, Cisco Switches and Routers VPN VMWear installed, configured, connected DNS for Windows and Linix installed, configured, connected Database: SQL 2000 2008 and 2012 Active Directory NT-2012, User Account set up, File shares, Creating folders, User and Group Policies, File Shares etc.
- Telephony Server Administration for Cisco Phone Systems Client Stations: Windows95-10 Pro, Ubuntu Windows Server 7,8,2000, 2012, Server Essentials 2012, Exchange 2003-16, Support for Citrix and Windows, Terminal Server environments and Thin Clients.
- Knowledge of Citrix SMS server administration.
- Avigilon Admin, Lenel, Viakoo and Genetec Physical Security Systems including dashboards for systems.
- Unix Sun, Solaris 2.5, 2.6.

- Creative and efficient makes this assignment for Yahoo my favorite.
- I programmed an, impressive, block of code using PHP, JS and XML; including composing an exceptional instruction guide for the system developers at Yahoo, whom were able to apply the FTP and DB connections as required, for trouble free, integration in less than 15 hours.
- Launching the finished application, pulled one snap shot image from eight different but local, security cameras.
- Stored the images on a remote DB server then redirected the images to a web browser which displayed as one single image.
- The images were to appear first as a thumbnail.
- Clicking the thumbnail would enlarge the image, seamlessly, as one image; providing a constant updated, live image for viewing.
- While completing this task, I developed a way to apply this framework to multiple brands of security cameras, providing N2N Secure, with
 a lucrative framework for future clients.
- Succeeded in installing a working Windows 2012, Lenel Dashboard system which connected to a local AD and LDAP using a single sign on
- I was able to accomplish this without any prior training or assistance from Lenel support.
- Lenel is a complicated, "Closed community" Security program.
- Accomplishing this project showcased my aptitude and engineering abilities.
- Conserving on support agreements provided available funds to purchase other equipment and software to accelerate the success of the company.
- Working with VIP Clients such as HP, Glassdoor, eBay, Facebook and SunPower and Stripe also provided a valuable experience.
- Duties: Assembling VPN access for corporate network.
- Install and Configure Active Directory and DNS Server.
- Identify, create and define the application requirements.
- Define data structures and application solutions, including server-side administration and implementing and improving firewall security as well as mapping out physical topology of the network.
- Define application solutions appropriate to customer requirements.
- Code, document and implement project specifications programs.
- Test, code and perform unit test plan for programs assigned.
- Integrate with 3rd party applications.
- Define physical program units and data structures.
- Provide Pen testing and Microsoft Baseline Analyzer Reports to Security Manager for review.
- Skills and Tools Used: Windows Sever 2008 and Fortigate 200B POE firewall, Nmap, Microsoft Baseline Analyzer, Linux Backtrack, and Kali Linux and Nessus, Cloud Servers and VMWare to setup corporate office and working lab environments.
- I also worked with other access control systems and was trained in the Avigilon administration.

January 2013 - January 2014 SUPPORT SPECIALIST Chickasaw Nation Industries | Lenexa

- Deployment of Epic system regional wide.
- Pleased to have worked while attending classes full time.
- My greatest achievement with CDI was learning a new software and becoming educated in the medical industry.
- Duties included: Updating and configuring Windows 7 system to newmedical records software with compliance for Citrix Server to function with legacy systems.
- Provide support for Hillcrest Medical Center.
- Used server related tools to resolve user issues.
- Work with other team members to install and update equipment, Items included: Arm Band, Printers, Document scanners, (COW)-Cart on Wheels, installed new switches and monitors, Cisco 7960 Phone systems, credit card systems.
- Documentation and updated paper work for billing of Printer use.
- Installed Citrix server software and configured to connect to one of 20 Citrix servers at corporate office in Temple Texas, worked with Remedy Ticket system.
- And a new system called Service now.
- Also, managed and updated Microsoft Share Point for inventory and Identification Management of new and older equipment installations.
- TEKsystems 2009.

$SCCM\ ADMINISTRATOR\ |\ TEXAS\ DEPARTMENT\ OF\ INFORMATION\ RESOURCES\ 3mth\ Contract\ |\ City\ ,\ STATE$

- Completed project requiring the placement of all company software on a SMS server.
- In addition, I built software packages for servers involving MSI file structure and MST file structure and.
- wrote VBS scripts to communicate with Active Directory, providing login rights to map drives which also worked with company applications.
- 5 | Page.

Education

Associate of Applied Science Degree:

AAS: Network Security Texas State Technical College, City, State Network Security

Associates Applied Science Degree:

AAS: Computer Science Web Development and design Texas State Technical College, City, State Computer Science Web Development and design

CISCO Networking Academy I, II, III Net Pro Certification, ID UG56 ID CJ8X A+ Certification Training Global Knowledge:
Diploma: Tri-County Technology Center Bartlesville, OK Avigilon Administration Bachler Degree equivalent with over 155 credit hours, plus years of experience in the field of Information Technology.
Skills

ASP.Net, A+ Certification, Accounting Software, Acrylic, Active Directory, administrative, Dream Weaver, AD, Ant, automate, Backup Exec, backup, billing, C++, CISCO, Citrix, Client and Server, ColdFusion, Cold Fusion, HARDWARE, network systems, credit, encryption, CSS3, Client, Clients, DATABASE, Dell, Documentation, DNS, editing, Ethernet, XML, firewall, FLASH, Front Page 2000, FTP, funds, Ghost, HP, HTML, HTML5, PHP, image, Imaging, Information security, information systems, Information Technology, instruction, inventory, IP, IPX/SPX, JavaScript, J query, LDAP, Linux 6.1, Linux, McAfee, Access, Excel, Exchange, office, MS Office97, Outlook, Power Point, MS Project, Microsoft Share Point, SQL 2000, Windows 7, Win, Windows, 2000, Windows 95,, Windows95, 98, NT, NT4.0, Word, monitors, MSI, My SQL, Enterprise, NETWORK ADMINISTRATION, Network Architecture, network hardware, Networking Hardware, NETWORK SECURITY, NETWORKING, Network, Norton, Novell 5.0, DB, OSI, Page, Payroll, pc's, PC Anywhere, Pen, Phone Systems, Camera, cameras, Policies, presenting, Printer, Printers, processes, progress, PROTOCOLS, quality, Red Hat 7, Report Writer, requirement, risk analysis, Routers, scanners, Servers, scripts, Scripting, SMS, SNMP, Solaris 2.5, SQL, Sun, switches, Cisco Switches, TCP/IP, Desktop support, Telephony, Telnet, Terminal Server, Transmission, Unix, Unix2.6, VPN, Visio, Vision, Visual Studio, Windows Server 7